Radosław Roszczyk

Curriculum Vitae

Faculty of Electrical Engineering
Warsaw University of Technology

℘ (+48) 604-570-290

⋈ radoslaw.roszczyk@pw.edu.pl

www.roszczyk.net

A specialist in biomedical image analysis and processing, machine learning, data analysis and distributed systems. He has experience in these areas in the development of new methods and their application in a wide range of scientific and technical fields, including: biomedical engineering, measurement systems, machine vision systems.

Education

2021: PhD, Computer Science, Warsaw University of Technology.

Three-dimensional reconstruction of the intestinal glands based on the sequence of microscopic images

2014: Master of Engineering, Computer Science, Warsaw University of Life Sciences.

Non-classical methods for credit risk rating using Data Mining techniques

2008: Bachelor of Engineering, Life Sciences, Warsaw University of Life Sciences.

Highbush lueberry (Vaccinium corymbosum L.) cultivation in Poland

2005: Bachelor of Engineering, Information Technology, Warsaw University of Technology.

"System Analityk" as tool for data exploration in customer relationship management systems

Research Experience

Warsaw University of Technology

2024 – now **DoorCE**, EU.

System architect and key programmer. Responsible for the design and core functionality of the system. Programming languages used: C#, JavaScript.

2022 – 2023 *Mediteller*, EU.

Technology consultant for the digitisation of resources representing the cultural heritage of European rural areas

2019 – 2021 **Baltic Large Scale Computing**, Interreg.

Key programmer and system designer. Responsible for the core functionality of the platform. Programming languages used: C#, JavaScript, Python.

2015 – 2016 Methods and algorithms of quantitative morphometry in computer analysis of microscopic images of tumours and other lesions in pathomorphology, NCN.

Design of algorithms for tissue segmentation and extraction of anatomical structures. Programming languages used: Matlab

Professional Experience

2024 – . . . Warsaw University of Technology, Vice-Dean for Student Affairs.

- cooperation with the Faculty Council of the Student Government,
- chairing the Faculty Scholarship Committee and coordinating the university scholarship campaign,
- coordination of student internships and cooperation with companies in this area,
- supervision over student's social and living issues,
- matters related to student's disciplinary responsibility,
- cooperation with secondary schools and the WUT Communication and Promotion Office.

2021 - . . . Warsaw University of Technology, Assistant Professor.

- research related to the processing of medical images and application of neural networks,
- supervision of student's theses and research projects,
- conducting lectures, projects, workshops and other activities for students,
- conducting own projects and research.

- 2014 2021 Warsaw University of Technology, Scientific Researcher / Lecturer.
 - participation in research projects,
 - teaching students,
 - teacher training in Python programming (CMI).
- 2017 2019 **Crawford**, senior developer.
 - − design and implementation of tools for new insurance programmes C#,
 - creating applications for internal company needs C#,
 - reporting based on SQL.
- 2005 2015 JVC Poland / JVC Kenwood Corporation, senior developer / IT manager.
 - design and implementation of interface to the ERP system − C#,
 - creation of dedicated applications to business needs and end customers (C#, .NET),
 - building and maintaining relationships with corporate IT personnel, customers, suppliers and vendors,
 - special expertise in ERP System on the corporate level.
- 1999 2019 **Widget**, senior developer / senior consultant.
 - making additions to ERP system C#,
 - creation of dedicated applications to business needs and end customers C#,
 - implementation of ERP systems (accounting and payroll modules) for customers.

Publications

Journal Articles

- 2023 Kamil Rybiński, Michał Śmiałek, Agris Sostaks, Krzysztof Marek, **Radosław Roszczyk**, and Marek Wdowiak. Visual low-code language for orchestrating large-scale distributed computing. **Journal of Grid Computing**, volume 21, pages 1–28, 2023.
- 2023 Lukasz Kamiński, Maciej Kozłowski, Daniel Sporysz, Katarzyna M Węgrzyn-Wolska, Patryk Zaniewski, and Radosław Roszczyk. Comparative review of selected internet communication protocols. Foundations of Computing & Decision Sciences, volume 48, pages 39–56, 2023.
- 2022 Piotr Zych, **Radosław Roszczyk**, Jan Sroka, and Ken Kawamata. The phenomena of bursts by opening low-voltage relay. *Energies*, volume 15, 2022.
- 2021 Tomasz Markiewicz, Małgorzata Lorent, and **Radosław Roszczyk**. Abstract: 3d reconstruction of kidney with tumour based on histopathological macroscopic imaging. *Virchows Archiv*, volume 479, 2021.
- 2021 Krzysztof Marek, Michał Śmiałek, Kamil Rybiński, **Radosław Roszczyk**, and Marek Wdowiak. Balticlsc: Low-code software development platform for large scale computations. *Computing and Informatics*, volume 40, pages 734–753, 2021.
- 2020 Michał Śmiałek, Kamil Rybiński, **Radosław Roszczyk**, and Krzysztof Marek. Towards a unified requirements model for distributed high performance computing. In Aneta Poniszewska-Marańda, Natalia Kryvinska, Stanisław Jarząbek, and Lech Madeyski, editors, *Data-Centric Business and Applications*, volume 40 of *Lecture Notes on Data Engineering and Communications Technologies*, pages 1–20. 2020.
- 2020 Radosław Roszczyk, Izabela Antoniuk, and Artur Krupa. Normal patch retinex robust alghoritm for white balancing in digital microscopy. *Machine Graphics & Vision*, volume 29, 2020.

In Conference Proceedings

- 2024 Maciej Dragun and **Radosław Roszczyk**. Neural network-based approach to eye disease classification from fundus images. In *Proceedings of the 25th International Conference on Computational Problems of Electrical Engineering (CPEE 2024*), pages 1–4, 2024.
- 2024 Justyna Budzyńska, Maria Kujawa, and Radosław Roszczyk. Applying artificial intelligence techniques in computed tomography for supporting liver cancer diagnosis. In 2024 Progress in Applied Electrical Engineering (PAEE), pages 1–6, 2024.

- 2023 Aleksander Zamojski, Kacper Jarczak, and Radosław Roszczyk. Fetal brain imaging: A composite neural network approach for keyframe detection in ultrasound videos. In 2023 Progress in Applied Electrical Engineering (PAEE), 2023.
- 2023 Ada Szmygin, Marcin Wojtowicz, Żaneta Świderska Chadaj, and **Radosław Roszczyk**. Prediction of athletes' performance results using machine learning algorithms. In *Proceedings of the 24th International Conference on Computational Problems of Electrical Engineering CPEE 2023*, 2023.
- 2022 Piotr Zych, Konrad Sobolewski, Jan Sroka, Radosław Roszczyk, and Ken Kawamata. Comparative analysis of electric arc by simulation tests and practical measurements of a simple relay. In 2022 23rd International Conference on Computational Problems of Electrical Engineering (CPEE), pages 1–4, 2022.
- 2022 Krzysztof Berski, Krzysztof Wilk, and **Radosław Roszczyk**. Three-dimensional reconstruction of the kidney. In *2022 23rd International Conference on Computational Problems of Electrical Engineering (CPEE)*, pages 1–4, 2022.
- 2021 Radosław Roszczyk, Marek Wdowiak, Michał Śmiałek, Kamil Rybiński, and Krzysztof Marek. Balticlsc: A low-code hpc platform for small and medium research teams. In *IEEE Symposium on Visual Languages and Human Centric Computing (VL/HCC)*, pages 1–4, 2021.
- 2021 Patryk Nowacki, **Radosław Roszczyk**, and Artur Krupa. Distributed event queue management system. In 2021 22nd International Conference on Computational Problems of Electrical Engineering (CPEE), pages 1–4, 2021.
- 2019 **Radosław Roszczyk**, Tomasz Markiewicz, Robert Koktysz, and Szczepan Cierniak. Active contour method for segmentation of the glands in colon histology images. In Andrzej Napieralski, editor, *Proceedings of 26th International Conference Mixed Design of Integrated Circuits and Systems MIXDES 2019*, pages 1–4. Lodz University of Technology, Department of Microelectronics and Computer Science, 2019.
- 2015 **Radosław Roszczyk**, Tomasz Markiewicz, Robert Koktysz, and Wojciech Kozłowski. Metody aktywnego konturu w segmentacji i określaniu obwiedni przekrojów gruczołów jelita. In *XIX Krajowa Konferencja Biocybernetyka i Inżynieria Biomedyczna*, page 197. IBIB PAN, 2015.
- 2012 Tomasz Krupa, **Radosław Roszczyk**, and Cezary Piestrzeniewicz. Czynniki wpływajce na efektywność zapylenia kwiatów borówki wysokiej. In *Czynniki wpływające na plonowanie i jakość owoców roślin sadowniczych*, pages 79–88. Katedra Sadownictwa SGGW, 2012.
- 2010 Tomasz Krupa and Radosław Roszczyk. Znaczenie trzmieli w zapyleniu kwiatów borówki wysokiej. In Nauka praktyce: XLVI ogólnopolska naukowa konferencja sadownicza, pages 41–44. Instytut Ogrodnictwa Skierniewice, 2010.

Certificate

- 2012 Microsoft Certified Technology Specialist
- 2006 Microsoft Certified Professional

Membership

- 2016 ... Polish Information Processing Society, PTI, #2502.
- 2016 ... Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers, *IEEE*, #93948003.
- 2015 ... International Society for Horticultural Science, ISHS, #39170.

Academic Achievements & Recognitions

2024 **XXV** Conference Computational Problems of Electrical Engineering (CPEE2020). 10-13th, September 2024, Poland - Member of Program Committee and Organising Committee

2024 17th Conference on Computer Science and Inteligence Systems, (IEEE #54150, ranked B in CORE).

8-11th, September 2024, Belgrade, Serbia - Program Committee

2022 Nagroda: Złota Kreda za rok akademicki 2021/2022 w kategorii Najlepszy Prowadzący ćwiczenia, laboratoria, projekty lub seminaria.

26th, November 2022

2022 17th Conference on Computer Science and Inteligence Systems, (IEEE #54150, ranked B in CORE).

4-7th, September 2022, Sofia, Bulgaria - Program Committee

2020 XXI Conference Computational Problems of Electrical Engineering (CPEE2020).

16-19th, September 2020, Poland - Member of Organising Committee

Courses and Training

DeepLearning.Al - Coursera

- Improving Deep Neural Networks: Hyperparameter Tuning, Regularization and Optimization
- Sequence Models
- Introduction to TensorFlow for Artificial Intelligence, Machine Learning, and Deep Learning
- Al for Medical Prognosis
- Convolutional Neural Networks in TensorFlow
- Convolutional Neural Networks
- Al For Medical Treatment
- Neural Networks and Deep Learning
- Structuring Machine Learning Projects
- Al for Medical Diagnosis

Johns Hopkins University – Coursera

- The Data Scientist's Toolbox
- Practical Machine Learning
- Exploratory Data Analysis
- Regression Models
- R Programming
- Statistical Inference
- Getting and Cleaning Data
- Developing Data Products

Polish Academy of Sciences

Mining massive datasets

Microsoft

- Administering Microsoft SQL Server 2012 Databases
- Administering and Automating Microsoft SQL Server 2005
- Creating Reporting Solutions using Microsoft SQL Server 2000
- Reporting Services Designing and Implementing OLAP Solutions Using Microsoft SQL Server 2000
- Designing and Populating a Data Warehouse with Microsoft SQL Server 2000
- Implementing a Data Warehouse with Microsoft SQL Server 2012
- Maintaining a Microsoft SQL Server 2005
- Database Mining massive datasets Programming a Microsoft SQL Server 2000

Programming with C#

Teaching

2014 - ... Warsaw University of Technology.

- Języki i metody programowania
- Podstawy programowania
- Programowanie usług w chmurze
- Testowanie i weryfikacja oprogramowania
- Metodyki wytwarzania oprogramowania
- Sieci komputerowe
- Przetwarzanie obrazów medycznych
- Elektrotechnika i elektronika
- Teoria obwodów
- Podstawy elektromagnetyzmu
- Komputerowa analiza i projektowanie obwodów elektrycznych
- Matematyka Metody numeryczne w technice